<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Azure | Small pieces]]></title>
  <link href="http://krrrcks.github.io/blog/categories/azure/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://krrrcks.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-05T11:30:26+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://krrrcks.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krrrcks]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind the storage driver for Ubuntu cloud images (on Azure)]]></title>
    <link href="http://krrrcks.github.io/blog/2014/07/24/mind-the-storage-driver-for-ubuntu-cloud-images-on-azure/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-24T12:30:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://krrrcks.github.io/blog/2014/07/24/mind-the-storage-driver-for-ubuntu-cloud-images-on-azure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago I wanted to build Firefox OS' newest release for a
friend. Because I did not wanted these GB of code, binaries etc. on my
notebook I fired up an Ubuntu image on Microsoft Azure. I feared that
at a certain point in the build process I may had to download
everything to my local machine and therefore I installed Docker via a
simple</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install docker.io
</code></p>

<p>Then I started the build process as laid out on Mozilla&rsquo;s Developer
Network. But, during downloading the source code (that&rsquo;s about 12 GB
of Git repositories from Mozilla and Android), I got a &ldquo;no more space
left on device&rdquo;. That was strange: I had a 100 GB volume attached to
the VM and enough space and inodes left. After some searching I asked
on the IRC channel and got a good hint: &ldquo;What&rsquo;s your storage driver?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Well, I thought that it&rsquo;s AUFS; I wanted to add &ldquo;as usual&rdquo; because
AUFS was available on my notebook from the beginning. But a <code>docker.io
info</code> gave me:</p>

<p><code>
$ sudo docker.io info
Containers: 0
Images: 0
Storage Driver: devicemapper
 Pool Name: docker-8:1-131188-pool
 Data file: /var/lib/docker/devicemapper/devicemapper/data
 Metadata file: /var/lib/docker/devicemapper/devicemapper/metadata
 Data Space Used: 291.5 Mb
 Data Space Total: 102400.0 Mb
 Metadata Space Used: 0.7 Mb
 Metadata Space Total: 2048.0 Mb
Execution Driver: native-0.1
Kernel Version: 3.13.0-29-generic
WARNING: No swap limit support
</code></p>

<p>I then learned that somehow the DeviceMapper driver only allows a
certain amount of diffs and I reached that amount with my build
process. (Maybe it&rsquo;s possible to relax that restriction but I do not
know how.)</p>

<p>I learned as well that the Ubuntu cloud image that is provided by
Microsoft Azure doesn&rsquo;t have AUFS support. Therefore Docker uses the
DeviceMapper storage driver instead. After I installed the AUFS
support I could export the images, change the storage driver and
import the images again.</p>

<p>It would be nice seeing the Docker documentation being more detailed
on those storage drivers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
